# Hardik Bhut

# Lead iOS Developer

#### **GET IN CONTACT**

Mobile: +91-9998376827

Email: hardikbhut.1986@gmail.com Address: Pune, Maharashtra - 411057

# **PERSONAL DETAILS**

• Total Experience 14 Years 4Months

Current Location Pune
 Date of Birth Jan 26, 1986

Gender Male Marrial Status Married

#### **SKILLS**

- IOS App Development Using Swift SwiftUI And ObjectiveC.
- Architectures: MVC MVVM MVP.
- Languages: Swift SwiftUI ObjectiveC & JavaScript.
- CoreData SQLite UIKit CoreGraphics
   CoreLocation Mapkit Google Maps API
   CoreBluetooth & Other Popular Dependencies.
- Xcode CodeAl Instrument SPM CocoaPods Swift Packages Cartrage.
- Development: SOLID & DRY Principles Memory Management And Security Checks.
- CI/CD With Dev Ops
- Push Notification FCM
- Memory Management And Performance Optimization
- Unit Testing And Debugging
- Auto Layout And Interface Builder
- Apple Human Interface Guidelines (HIG)
- App Store Submission And Distribution

Process • RESTful APIs And JSON

• Git Version Control

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Lead IOS Development
- Team Management With Agile Methodology Scrums And Sprint Planning.
- Problem Solving

#### LANGUAGES KNOWN

- English
- Hindi
- Gujarati

#### **SOCIAL LINKS**

https://www.linkedin.com/in/hardik-bhut-0b974a29/

14+years of experience in software engineering. 12years of experience iOS app development and Team lead.

More then 10 app upload on app store, Experience. with Swift, Objective-C, XCode, different iOS versions, debugging tools, memory management, threading techniques, UI design.

Experienced in gathering requirements on project needs from various stakeholders and in working with cross-functional team members.

Lead team of 4-5 people for Enterprise applications, also worked as an individual contributor.

Project managed using SCRUM/Agile methodologies.

#### **EDUCATION HISTORY**

#### Post Graduation

Course MCA( Computers )
College Gujarat University

Year of Passing 2009

#### Graduation

Course B.Com( Commerce )
College Gujarat University

Year of Passing 2006

# **EXPERIENCE**

Dec 2018 to June 2024

Lead iOS Developer at Krios Info Solution Pvt.Ltd (Mahindra & Mahindra)

Led a team of 4-5 people for M4U Enterprise applications, also worked as an individual contributor.

Client Collaboration: On payroll of Krios info Solution worked for Mahindra & Mahindra

Responsibilities: Understanding requirements from Product

Owner. Meticulously formulated it in stories on Azure Devops , personally oversaw development process.

 $\label{lem:effectively} \mbox{ Effectively delegated tasks to other team members.}$ 

Informing blockers and backlogs if any. Providing 1:1

feedback and conducting interviews for hiring.

Team Leadership: Led a team through 15+ successful Agile

sprints and deliver on time.

Skills: Swift, Objective C ,SwiftUI, Rest API and SOAP API, Azure Devops

# Apr 2017 to Sep 2018

Senior iOS Developer (Team lead - mobile team ) at Squirrel Softech Services

Monitored team to ensure efficient development, design, testing, and documentation of the Analytic app. Analyzed and understood the requirements of the apps thoroughly. Provided accurate

timelines for app development and delivery

# **COURSES & CERTIFICATIONS**

- SwiftUI 5, & Swift5.9 Build iOS App By Udemy
- Programming Foundations: Conducting code Reviews By LinkedIn

#### Mar 2016 to Mar 2017

#### Senior Mobile (iOS) application developer at Venture foundry

Monitored team to ensure efficient development, design, testing, and documentation of the Analytic app. Analyzed and understood the requirements of the apps thoroughly. Provided accurate timelines for app development and delivery

#### Aug 2015 to Feb 2016

#### Senior iOS developer at Quix creation

Leading, UI design, development, testing, communication to client

#### Nov 2014 to Aug 2015

#### Senior iOS Developer at smarData Enterprises i Itd

UI design, development, testing, communication to client

#### May 2014 to Nov 2014

### Senior iOS Developer at bito1

senior iOS developer developing and also test the app

# Apr 2012 to Apr 2014

#### iOS developer at S.k Solution(Pidex)

Software Developer for iOS and .NET

#### Sep 2009 to Apr 2012

# .Net Developer at eSence Pvt Ltd Navneet Gala Prakashan

software developer in .NET

# **PROJECTS**

#### Mahindra For You (06/2023 - Present)

Vehicle booking platform for Mahindra & Mahindra where End Customers can track progress of his vehicle booked at dealership

Skills: Swift, Objective C , Rest and SOAP API, Azure Devops, Cocoa Pods, Packages Cartage, CI/CD With Dev Ops, RESTful APIs And JSON, Git Version Control

# With You Hamesha (04/2019 - 05/2023)

End to end Vehicle Service Management platform for Mahindra & Mahindra Where user can book vehicle service, various scheme purchase, payments; Do Live chat with customer care & Chat Bots.

Skills: Swift, Objective C , Rest API and SOAP API, Azure Devops, Cocoa Pods, RESTful APIs And JSON, Git Version Control

Experienced professional with a proven track record of delivering and providing support for over **25 diverse applications**.